Guide to the Susan H. Douglas political Americana collection, [1783?]-1961.
Douglas, Susan H. Political Americana Collection, [1783?]-1961
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Susan H. Douglas Political Americana Collection, [1783?]-1961.
2214
Douglas, Susan Havey
86 cubic ft.
Cartoons, prints, and posters; lapel buttons, ribbons, medals, textiles, hats, and other costume items; ballots, broadsides, leaflets, and other ephemera; pamphlets and other formal publications; sheet music and songbooks; scrapbooks; and three-dimensional items.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Approximately 5,500 promotional and commemorative items in a variety of formats, including cartoons, prints, and posters; lapel buttons, ribbons, medals, textiles, hats, and other costume items; ballots, broadsides, leaflets, and other ephemera; pamphlets and other formal publications; sheet music and songbooks; scrapbooks; and three-dimensional items relating to United States presidential campaigns, as well as a small amount of material on candidates for other offices.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Approximately 5,500 promotional and commemorative items in a variety of formats, including cartoons, prints, and posters; lapel buttons, ribbons, medals, textiles, hats, and other costume items; ballots, broadsides, leaflets, and other ephemera; pamphlets and other formal publications; sheet music and songbooks; scrapbooks; and three-dimensional items relating to United States presidential campaigns, as well as a small amount of material on candidates for other offices.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Douglas, Susan Havey
Subjects:
Political campaigns--United States.; Presidents--United States--Election.; Campaign insignia.; Campaign paraphernalia.; Campaign songs.; Electioneering--United States.; Elections--United States.; Political slogans.
Form and Genre Terms:
Autographs.; Badges.; Ballots.; Broadsides.; Brochures.; Buttons (information artifacts).; Pamphlets.; Political Cartoons.; Leaflets.; Lithographs.; Medals.; Photographs.; Portraits.; Posters.; Prints.; Scrapbooks.; Sheet music.; Songbooks.; Tableware; Textiles.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Ballots
This series includes paper ephemera related to the voter registration and voting processes. The bulk of the series is comprised of paper ballots intended to have been deposited by voters in ballot boxes to reflect their choice of candidates. In the 19th century, many of these ballots were printed by commercial printers and were heavily decorated. As the century progressed, paper ballots increasingly were printed by governmental agencies until their eventual replacement by voting machines. The series also contains petitions, applications, sample ballots showing how to use voting machines, and other instructional materials for voters
Series II. Bric-a-Brac
This series is comprised of three-dimensional promotional items, ranging from tableware and glassware to matchbooks, phonograph records, and ashtrays. As its name implies, this is a true "grab bag" category. The bulk of Bric-a-Brac items are utilitarian in nature, and were decorated to promote or demonstrate allegiance to particular candidates.
Series III. Books
Susan Douglas donated a small quantity of books to Cornell, most of which are secondary reference sources on American politics. Items in the "Books" category will not be digitized by the Political Americana Project.
Series IV. Broadsides
This series contains an assortment of promotional, declaratory, and advertising items. Most of these items are made of paper, advertised particular events or politically-related products, and were intended to have a very short use-life. Mrs. Douglas also included some of the collection's bumper stickers in this category.
Series V. Buttons
This series is predominantly composed of combination items made of plastic, metal, and paper. Button technology was developed by the Whitehead & Hoag company of Newark, New Jersey, and was used extensively starting in the 1896 Presidential campaign. Celluloid plastic was used exclusively until the 1940s; the buttons frequently are referred to as "celluloid buttons". Many early buttons contained actual photographic portraits. Subsequent development of a lithographic printing technique for all-metal buttons made for less costly manufacture, but also limited the type of imagery that could be applied. Mrs. Douglas also included lapel tabs in this category. Almost all of the items in this series have been cataloged as groups rather than at the item level.
Series VI. Cartoons
This series contains political cartoons and caricatures in a number of mediums. Many 19th century cartoons are in the form of lithographic prints. Some of the later examples include cartoons clipped from newspapers and magazines.
Series VII. Maps & Charts
This series is comprised of a series of graphic materials ranging from representations of national politics (showing which states voted for which candidates, etc.) to political convention floor plans. Some of these items were published in book form, which included large fold-out maps and charts.
Series VIII. Pamphlets
This series contains a wide variety of text-based materials, including soft-covered books (particularly the "text books" issued by parties for particular elections and campaign biographies), smaller pamphlets, periodicals, brochures, and leaflets. Some of the items have frequent illustrations. A limited number of invitations and advertisements also were included in this category.
Series IX. Parades
This series contains a variety of artifacts that were carried in political parades or other public events. They range in size from small pennants to very large parade banners, and in form from replica axes and guns to hats and helmets, kerosene "torch lights", lanterns, and walking sticks. Mrs. Douglas also included a limited amount of materials advertising parade items in this category. There is significant overlap between the "Parades" and "Wearing Apparel" categories.
Series X. Paper Miscellaneous
This category includes a wide variety of paper items intended to have a short use-life, including admission tickets, membership cards, post cards, fundraising letters and brochures, advertising cards, certificates, stationery, and stamps. Mrs. Douglas also included stereocard and cabinet photographs and some of the collection's bumper stickers in this category. Some of the items in this series (particularly post card sets) have been cataloged as groups rather than at the item level.
Series XI. Posters
This series is primarily comprised of large political portrait images intended for public or home display.
Series XII. Prints
This series is primarily comprised of smaller political portrait images intended for public or home display, although Mrs. Douglas also included a number of two-page images from newspaper center-spreads. 19th century lithographs and wood engravings make up a significant proportion of this category.
Series XIII. Ribbons
This series contains a variety of badges, most of which are at least in part textiles. Some of the items are still associated with their original metal pins.
Series XIV. Songbooks
This series includes materials facilitating song performance through provision of song lyrics and/or musical notation. Some of the items are in book form, gathering together several songs, while others are individual handbills.
Series XV. Sheet Music
This series is comprised of sheet music for politically-related songs and instrumentals. Many of these items contain elaborate cover illustrations.
Series XVI. Scrapbooks & Scrapbook Items
This series consists of 47 scrapbooks associated with particular election campaigns, one scrapbook on textiles, and individual items of particular note extracted from the scrapbooks. Mrs. Douglas included a combination of primary sources (particularly portraits but also a portion of a government document signed by Andrew Jackson) and secondary sources (especially newspaper and magazine clippings discussing electoral history) in her scrapbooks. Aside from extracted individual pieces, the scrapbooks will not be digitized by the Political Americana Project.
Series XVII. Trinkets
This series contains a variety of medals, medallions, pins, pendants, and other jewelry forms, including ferrotype portrait pins. Almost all of the items in this series have been cataloged as groups rather than at the item level. Mrs. Douglas artfully arranged these item groupings, frequently incorporating materials from other categories for visual effect.
Series XVIII. Textiles
This series contains a variety of politically-related textile forms, including bandanas, handkerchiefs, and yardage.
Series XIX. Wearing Apparel
This series consists of a variety of politically-related costume items, including neckties, hats and caps, suspenders, and even underwear. There is significant overlap between the "Wearing Apparel" and "Parades" categories.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Ballots
  This series includes paper ephemera related to the voter registration and voting processes. The bulk of the series is comprised of paper ballots intended to have been deposited by voters in ballot boxes to reflect their choice of candidates. In the 19th century, many of these ballots were printed by commercial printers and were heavily decorated. As the century progressed, paper ballots increasingly were printed by governmental agencies until their eventual replacement by voting machines. The series also contains petitions, applications, sample ballots showing how to use voting machines, and other instructional materials for voters
  - Ward Fifteen Regular Republican Ticket: Blaine & Logan, 1884; 2214.BA0001 (Box 102)
  - Democratic Ticket: Bryan & Sewall, 1896; 2214.BA0003 (Box 100)
  - Democratic Ticket: Bryan & Stevenson, 1900; 2214.BA0004 (Box 100)
  - Democratic Ticket: Breckinridge & Lane, 1860; 2214.BA0005 (Box 100)
  - Democratic Candidates: Buchanan & Breckinridge, ca. 1856; 2214.BA0006 (Box TBD)
  - Ballots of Half Century Ago: Buchanan & Breckinridge, ca. 1906; 2214.BA0007 (Box TBD)
  - Perth Amboy, New Jersey, Republican Sample Ballot, 1916; 2214.BA0008 (Box 97)
  - Sample Ballot, General Election, Third Congressional District, November 2, 1948; 2214.BA0009 (Box 94)
  - Voting Machine Sample Ballot: General Election, November 2, 1948; 2214.BA0010 (Box 94)
  - Voting Machine Sample Ballot: General Election, November 4, 1952; 2214.BA0011 (Box 94)
  - Eighth Ward Union Republican Ticket: Grant & Colfax, ca. 1868; 2214.BA0012 (Box 100)
  - Ward Ten Regular Republican Ticket: Grant & Wilson, ca. 1872; 2214.BA0013 (Box 102)
  - Election; Liberal Ticket, November 5, 1872; 2214.BA0014 (Box 102)
  - Democratic Ticket: Seymour & Blair, ca. 1868; 2214.BA0015 (Box 102)
  - Democratic Republican Ticket: Hancock & English, ca. 1880; 2214.BA0016 (Box 100)
  - Regular Democratic Ticket: Hancock & English, ca. 1880; 2214.BA0017 (Box 102)
  - National Union Ticket: Lincoln & Johnson, ca. 1864; 2214.BA0018 (Box 102)
  - Union Ticket: Lincoln & Johnson, ca. 1864; 2214.BA0019 (Box TBD)
  - Union ticket: Lincoln & Johnson, ca. 1864; 2214.BA0020 (Box 100)
  - Regular Republican Ticket: Lincoln & Hamlin, ca. 1860; 2214.BA0021 (Box 102)
  - Confederate States Electoral Ticket: Davis & Stephens, ca. 1861; 2214.BA0022 (Box 100)
  - Confederate States Virginia Electoral Ticket: Davis & Stephens, ca. 1861; 2214.BA0023 (Box 100)
  - Ward Eighteen Republican and Independent Ticket: Cleveland & Hendricks, 1884; 2214.BA0024 (Box TBD)
  - 4th Ward Democratic Conservative Ticket: Cleveland & Thurman, ca. 1888; 2214.BA0025 (Box TBD)
  - Democratic Ticket: Cleveland & Hendricks, ca. 1884; 2214.BA0026a (Box 100)
  - Democratic Ticket: Cleveland & Stevenson, 1892; 2214.BA0026b (Box 100)
  - Republican Ticket: McKinley & Hobart, 1896; 2214.BA0027 (Box 100)
  - Republican Ticket: McKinley & Hobart, 1896; 2214.BA0028 (Box 100)
  - This is your Sample Ballot: Progressive Party, ca. 1948; 2214.BA0029 (Box 102)
  - Save America: To Win with Willkie, ca. 1940; 2214.BA0030 (Box 97)
  - Democratic Electoral Ticket: Cass & Butler, ca. 1848; 2214.BA0031 (Box 100)
  - National Democratic Ticket: Palmer & Buckner, 1896; 2214.BA0032 (Box 100)
  - Republican Ticket: Benjamin Harrison & Reid, 1892; 2214.BA0033 (Box 100)
  - Union Labor Ticket: Streeter & Cuningham, ca. 1888; 2214.BA0034 (Box 102)
  - Burlington County National Greenback Labor Ticket, ca. 1876; 2214.BA0035 (Box TBD)
  - Democratic Ticket (local): Hezekiah B. Smith for Congress, ca. 1878-1880; 2214.BA0036 (Box 100)
  - Whig Ticket: James Bell for Governor, ca. 1854-1855; 2214.BA0037 (Box 100)
  - Mercer County Democratic Ticket: McClellan for Governor, ca. 1877; 2214.BA0038 (Box 100)
  - Democratic Ticket: James Carroll for Governor, ca. 1844; 2214.BA0039 (Box TBD)
  - Republican Ticket: Grant, ca. 1868; 2214.BA0040 (Box 100)
  - 17th Ward Ballot: Cass & Dickenson, ca. 1848; 2214.BA0042 (Box 100)
  - Voting Machine Sample Ballot: Primary Election, April 15, 1952; 2214.BA0043 (Map-case -)
  - Voting Machine Sample Ballot: General Election, November 7, 1944; 2214.BA0044 (Box 88)
  - Regular Democratic National Nominations: Douglas & Johnson, ca. 1860; 2214.BA0045 (Box 100)
  - Electoral Ticket: Buchanan & Breckinridge, ca. 1856; 2214.BA0046 (Box 100)
  - The Republican Ticket: Blaine & Logan, ca. 1884; 2214.BA0047 (Box 102)
  - Hamilton County, Ohio, Democratic Party Sample Ballot, ca. 1956; 2214.BA0048 (Box 94)
  - Voting Machine Sample Ballot: General Election, November 6, 1956; 2214.BA0049 (Box 97)
  - Hamilton County Sample Presidential Ballot: Eisenhower & Nixon, ca. 1956; 2214.BA0050 (Box 100)
  - Sample Ballot and Instructions for Voting: National and State Election, November 6, 1956; 2214.BA0051 (Map-case -)
  - Republican Poll Workers Form, 1908; 2214.BA0052 (Box 102)
  - Election Expenses Compact, ca. 1908; 2214.BA0053 (Box 102)
  - New Jersey Application for Military Service Ballot, 2214.BA0054 (Box 102)
  - New Jersey Petition for Presidential Candidate, 1952; 2214.BA0055 (Box 102)
- Series II. Bric-a-Brac
  Bric-a- Brac: This series is comprised of three-dimensional promotional items, ranging from tableware and glassware to matchbooks, phonograph records, and ashtrays. As its name implies, this is a true "grab bag" category. The bulk of Bric-a-Brac items are utilitarian in nature, and were decorated to promote or demonstrate allegiance to particular candidates.
  - John Quincy Adams Portrait Plaque, ca. 1852; 2214.BB0001 (Box 18)
  - "Gen. Chester A. Arthur" Portrait Collar Box, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0002 (Box 71)
  - Blaine-Logan Frog Paperweight or Door Stop, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0003 (Box 34)
  - Blaine Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0004 (Box 5)
  - Bryan "The People's Money" Portrait Glass Mug with Lid, ca. 1896; 2214.BB0005 (Box 22)
  - Bryan-Sewall "Sixteen To One" Portrait Drinking Glass, ca. 1896; 2214.BB0006 (Box 20)
  - Bryan-Kern Milk Glass Top Hat Coin Bank, ca. 1908; 2214.BB0007 (Box 64)
  - Bryan-Stevenson Portrait Metal Tray, 1900; 2214.BB0008 (Box 43)
  - Bryan "16-1" Metal Portrait Clock, ca. 1896; 2214.BB0009 (Box 50)
  - Henry Clay Glass Portrait Cup Plate, ca. 1844; 2214.BB0010 (Box 29)
  - Henry Clay Glass Portrait Paperweight, ca. 1844; 2214.BB0011 (Box 31)
  - Cleveland-Thurman Ceramic Portrait Pitcher, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0012 (Box 1)
  - Cleveland Kerosene Lamp, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0013 (Box 23)
  - Cleveland "Our Next President" Portrait Drinking Glass, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0014 (Box 20)
  - Cleveland Pressed Glass Portrait Plate, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0015 (Box 27)
  - Cleveland-Thurman Pressed Glass Portrait Tray, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0016 (Box 26)
  - Cleveland Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0017 (Box 13)
  - Cleveland Ceramic Portrait Tile, 1885; 2214.BB0018 (Box 17)
  - Cleveland Ceramic Portrait Tile, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0019 (Box 17)
  - "Dwight D. Eisenhower" Glass Portrait Paperweight, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0020 (Box 31)
  - Eisenhower Inauguration Commemorative Plate, ca. 1953; 2214.BB0021 (Box 6)
  - Eisenhower " I Like, you like, he likes ... Ike" Drinking Glass, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0022 (Box 21)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Drinking Glass, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0023 (Box 21)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Small Drinking Glass, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0024 (Box 21)
  - "This Year I'm Gonna Be Right!" Presidential Candidate Portrait Drinking Glass, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0025 (Box 21)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Portrait Plate, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0026 (Box 5)
  - "America's First Family: President And Mrs. Dwight D. Eisenhower" Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1953-1961; 2214.BB0027 (Box 6)
  - Presidential Portrait Plate, Washington through Eisenhower, ca. 1953; 2214.BB0028 (Box 7)
  - Eisenhower-Nixon "Our President and Vice-President" Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1953; 2214.BB0029 (Box 7)
  - Presidential Portrait Drinking Glass, ca. 1953; 2214.BB0030 (Box 20)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Ceramic Mug, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0031 (Box 3)
  - Eisenhower "I Like Ike" Paper Cup, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0032 (Box 76)
  - Eisenhower "We Like Ike" Metal Tray, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0033 (Box 42)
  - "Vote Republican" Jigger & Dice Shaker, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0033a (Box 76)
  - Magnetic Plastic Ashtray, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0033b (Box 76)
  - William H. Taft-Sherman "Grand Old Party, 1856 to 1908" Tin Portrait Plate, 2214.BB0034 (Box 47)
  - Cleveland-Thurman Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0035 (Box 13)
  - "Grover Cleveland" Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0036 (Box 13)
  - Tammany Hall Mechanical Coin Bank, 1873; 2214.BB0037 (Box 34)
  - Garfield Glass Portrait Serving Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0038 (Box 25)
  - Garfield Glass Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0039 (Box 28)
  - Garfield "We Mourn Our Nation's Loss" Glass Portrait Serving Plate, ca. 1881; 2214.BB0040 (Box 25)
  - "For President: James A. Garfield" Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0041 (Box 11)
  - Garfield Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0042 (Box 11)
  - Garfield-Arthur Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0043 (Box 11)
  - Garfield Ceramic Memorial Bowl, ca. 1881; 2214.BB0044 (Box 64)
  - Garfield Cast Iron Portrait Plaque, 2214.BB0045 (Box 44)
  - Garfield Portrait Drinking Glass, 2214.BB0046 (Box 21)
  - Garfield Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0047 (Box 11)
  - Garfield Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0048 (Box 11)
  - Hancock "For President" Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0049 (Box 12)
  - Arthur Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1880; 2214.BB0050 (Box 11)
  - Eisenhower Doll, 2214.BB0051 (Box 76)
  - Grant "Memorial" Glass Portrait Plate, ca. 1885; 2214.BB0052 (Box 28)
  - Grant "The Nation Mourns" Memorial Photograph and Frame, ca. 1885; 2214.BB0053 (Box 45)
  - "General U.S. Grant" Framed Medallion, ca. 1868; 2214.BB0054 (Box 72)
  - Grant "The Patriot And Soldier" Ceramic Mold Element?, ca. 1868; 2214.BB0055 (Box 30)
  - Grant Commemorative Plaster Wall Hanging, ca. 1885; 2214.BB0056 (Box 19)
  - "U.S. Grant" Small Porcelain Portrait Bust, 2214.BB0057 (Box 15)
  - Grant Small Porcelain Portrait Bust, 2214.BB0058 (Box 15)
  - Grant Terracotta Portrait Bust, 1885; 2214.BB0059 (Box 16)
  - Grant "The Patriot And Soldier" Glass Portrait Serving Plate, ca. 1868; 2214.BB0060 (Box 30)
  - Republican Centennial Commemorative Plate, 1954; 2214.BB0061 (Box 6)
  - Hendricks Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0062 (Box 5)
  - Blaine Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0063 (Box 5)
  - Morton "For Vice President" Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0064 (Box 12)
  - Benjamin Harrison-Morton Portrait Kerosene Lamp, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0065 (Box 23)
  - Harrison-Morton Pressed Glass Portrait Tray, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0066 (Box 26)
  - Benjamin Harrison Kerosene Lamp, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0067 (Box 23)
  - Benjamin Harrison "Our Next President" Drinking Glass, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0068 (Box 20)
  - Benjamin Harrison "The Same Old Hat" Glass Toothpick Holder, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0069 (Box 21)
  - Harrison-Morton Ceramic Portrait Pitcher, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0070 (Box 1)
  - Benjamin Harrison Ceramic Portrait Tile, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0071 (Box 17)
  - Benjamin Harrison Ceramic Portrait Plate, ca. 1888; 2214.BB0072 (Box 12)
  - Benjamin Harrison "1889-1893" Ceramic Portrait Plate, 2214.BB0073 (Box 12)
  - William Henry Harrison Log Cabin Plate, ca. 1840; 2214.BB0074 (Box 5)
  - William Henry Harrison Tortoise Shell Bowl, ca. 1840; 2214.BB0075 (Box 32)
  - E.G. Booz's Old Cabin Whiskey Bottle, ca. 1860-1870; 2214.BB0076 (Box 22)
  - William Henry Harrison "Tippecanoe/Fort Meigs" Cup Plate, ca. 1840; 2214.BB0077 (Box 29)
  - William Henry Harrison Glass Portrait Cup Plate, ca. 1840; 2214.BB0078 (Box 29)
  - William Henry Harrison Log Cabin Glass Cup Plate, ca. 1840; 2214.BB0079 (Box 29)
  - William Henry Harrison Pewter Teapot, ca. 1840; 2214.BB0080 (Box 40)
  - Benjamin Harrison Portrait Creamer, ca. 1933; 2214.BB0081 (Box 2)
  - Benjamin Harrison Portrait Match Case, 1888; 2214.BB0082 (Box 77)
  - Benjamin Harrison Ceramic Smoking Pipe, ca. 1892; 2214.BB0083 (Box 77)
  - Cleveland Portrait Pipe Bowl, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0084 (Box 77)
  - Cleveland-Thurman Wooden "Campaign Egg For 1888" with Case, 2214.BB0085 (Box 71)
  - Cleveland Portrait Match Case, 1888; 2214.BB0086 (Box 77)
  - Tyler Portrait Creamer, ca. 1933; 2214.BB0087 (Box 2)
  - Henry Clay Ceramic Portrait Pipe Bowl and Wooden Stem, 2214.BB0088 (Box 77)
  - Henry Clay Portrait Cigar Case, ca. 1844; 2214.BB0089 (Box 227)
  - Eisenhower Beanbag-weighted "I Like Ike" Ashtray, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0090 (Box 77)
  - Eisenhower Wooden Portrait Pipe, ca. 1952; 2214.BB0091 (Box 77)
  - Logan "G.A.R. Souvenir" Miniature Tin Canteen, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0092 (Box 45)
  - Logan Pressed Glass Portrait Plate, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0093 (Box 27)
  - Grant Pewter Portrait Bottle Cap, ca. 1868; 2214.BB0094 (Box 34)
  - Grant Portrait Match Case, ca. 1868; 2214.BB0095 (Box 77)
  - Grant Metal Portrait Match Holder, ca. 1868; 2214.BB0096 (Box 45)
  - Hobart Ceramic Portrait Plate, 1896; 2214.BB0097 (Box 9)
  - Hobart Ceramic Portrait Tray, 1896; 2214.BB0098 (Box 9)
  - Hobart Ceramic Portrait Tile, ca. 1896; 2214.BB0099 (Box 17)
  - Blaine-Logan Wooden Portrait Plaque, 1884; 2214.BB0100 (Box 74)
  - Cleveland-Hendricks Wooden Portrait Plaque, 1884; 2214.BB0101 (Box 74)
  - Cleveland Metal Portrait Plaque, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0102 (Box 46)
  - Hendricks Metal Portrait Plaque, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0103 (Box 46)
  - Butler Metal Portrait Plaque, ca. 1884; 2214.BB0104 (Box 46)
  - Hoover Ceramic Portrait Pitcher, ca. 1928; 2214.BB0105 (Box 4)
  - Hoover Ceramic Portrait Pitcher, ca. 1932; 2214.BB0106 (Box 4)
  - Hoover Inaugural Paperweight, 1929; 2214.BB0107 (Box 214)
  - Presidents of the United States Penknife with Case, ca. 1929; 2214.BB0108 (Box 72)
  - Al Smith Ceramic Portrait Pitcher, ca. 1928; 2214.BB0111 (Box 4)
  - Smith-Robinson Wall Plaque, ca. 1928; 2214.BB0112 (Box 75)
  - Landon Portrait Drinking Glass, ca. 1936; 2214.BB0113 (Box 21)
  - "Land-On Landon" Metal Donkey, 1936; 2214.BB0114 (Box 34)
  - Lincoln Portrait Painted on Glass, ca. 1900-1960; 2214.BB0116 (Box 143)
  - Lincoln Ceramic Portrait Urn, 2214.BB0117 (Box 64)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.BB0118 (Box -)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.BB0119 (Box -)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.BB0120 (Box -)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.BB0121 (Box -)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.BB0122 (Box -)
  - Item apparently not donated to Cornell University, 2214.BB0123 (Box -)
  - "Lincoln And The Union" Miniature Porcelain Mug, ca. 1860; 2214.BB0124 (Box 2)
  - Lincoln Portrait Photograph in Molded Thermoplastic "Vision of Ezechiel" Case, ca. 1861-1865; 2214.BB0125 (Box 71)